Submission review
Note: This review was done by Claude. Due to the amount of submissions, doing a fully manual review for each pull request is no longer feasible. Thank you for understanding.

Remember: The AI reviewer can be wrong - it may misread code, flag correct code as broken, or suggest changes that make things worse. Treat its findings as suggestions to verify, not instructions to follow blindly. You're responsible for the code you submit, so if a finding doesn't hold up, say so instead of changing working code to satisfy it.

Please address the following issues. The items in the collapsed sections are optional, so it's your call whether to address them.

There's no other multi-instance mod for Snipping Tool in the catalog, so this one fills a gap. A few things need fixing before merge:

1. The FindWindow* hooks can crash the process and break lookups within the same process (lines 55–59, 161–197)

FindWindowW/FindWindowExW accept a class atom as lpClassName (MAKEINTATOM(x), e.g. WC_DIALOG is MAKEINTATOM(0x8002)). IsSnippingWindow passes it straight to wcsstr, which dereferences an address below 0x10000 and crashes Snipping Tool. The caller doesn't have to be Snipping Tool's own code. Any DLL loaded in the process can make that call, for example the common Save dialog, shell extensions or accessibility code. Check IS_INTRESOURCE(cls) before treating it as a string.
The hooks return NULL for every matching lookup, including lookups of Snipping Tool's own windows in the same process. A FindWindowEx with a parent window is a child-window search, which can never detect another instance, yet it gets blocked too. Only other instances' windows need hiding. Call the original and skip results that belong to another process:
static bool IsSnippingWindow(LPCWSTR cls, LPCWSTR title) {
    if (cls && !IS_INTRESOURCE(cls) &&
        (wcsstr(cls, L"Snipper") || wcsstr(cls, L"SnippingTool"))) {
        return true;
    }
    ...
}

static bool IsOtherProcessWindow(HWND hWnd) {
    DWORD pid = 0;
    GetWindowThreadProcessId(hWnd, &pid);
    return pid != GetCurrentProcessId();
}

HWND WINAPI FindWindowExW_Hook(HWND hwndParent, HWND hwndChildAfter,
                               LPCWSTR lpszClass, LPCWSTR lpszWindow) {
    HWND hWnd = FindWindowExW_Original(hwndParent, hwndChildAfter, lpszClass,
                                       lpszWindow);
    if ((hwndParent && hwndParent != HWND_MESSAGE) ||
        !IsSnippingWindow(lpszClass, lpszWindow)) {
        return hWnd;
    }

    // Skip the windows of other Snipping Tool instances.
    while (hWnd && IsOtherProcessWindow(hWnd)) {
        hWnd = FindWindowExW_Original(hwndParent, hWnd, lpszClass, lpszWindow);
    }
    return hWnd;
}

HWND WINAPI FindWindowW_Hook(LPCWSTR lpClassName, LPCWSTR lpWindowName) {
    return FindWindowExW_Hook(nullptr, nullptr, lpClassName, lpWindowName);
}
2. @include snippingtool.exe also matches the modern Windows 11 Snipping Tool (line 9)

The new Snipping Tool app (the Microsoft.ScreenSketch package) also runs as SnippingTool.exe, from C:\Program Files\WindowsApps\.... Because @include matches by file name, the mod loads into that app too. The broad "SnippingTool" / "Snipping Tool" substring matches then turn its named mutexes into unnamed ones and hide its windows, even though the mod isn't meant for that app. The legacy tool always runs from System32, so match its full path (@include supports environment variables):

// @include         %SystemRoot%\System32\SnippingTool.exe
3. The mutex hooks are probably on the wrong module, and their name matching is too broad (lines 41–53, 203–209)

Wh_SetFunctionHook((void*)CreateMutexW, ...) hooks the kernel32.dll export. The real implementation is in kernelbase.dll, and Windows' own binaries such as snippingtool.exe import synchronization APIs through API sets (api-ms-win-core-synch-*) that resolve directly to kernelbase. So these hooks most likely never fire for Snipping Tool's own calls. Check the mod log: if Intercepted CreateMutexW never shows up, the FindWindow hooks alone are doing the work. Either remove the mutex hooks, or resolve the targets from kernelbase so that every caller is covered:
HMODULE kernelBase = GetModuleHandleW(L"kernelbase.dll");
auto pCreateMutexW =
    (decltype(&CreateMutexW))GetProcAddress(kernelBase, "CreateMutexW");
WindhawkUtils::SetFunctionHook(pCreateMutexW, CreateMutexW_Hook,
                               &CreateMutexW_Original);
// Same for CreateMutexExW and OpenMutexW.
win7-bsdr hooks CreateEventW this way.
IsSnippingMutex neutralizes any named mutex containing SnippingTool, InitializingMutex or Snipper, so it can also catch mutexes created by other components loaded in the process and silently break their cross-process synchronization. The README already names the one mutex that matters, so compare against that exact name instead, using the name your log shows, including any Local\ prefix. lm-regedit-multi-instance does the same with an exact class-name match.
Optional improvements

Minor polish — none of this affects users, so it's your call.

Use WindhawkUtils::SetFunctionHook with decltype(&Func) instead of hand-written function pointer typedefs and (void*)/(void**) casts. It's type-checked, so a signature mismatch becomes a compile error:
decltype(&FindWindowW) FindWindowW_Original;
...
WindhawkUtils::SetFunctionHook(FindWindowW, FindWindowW_Hook, &FindWindowW_Original);
Remove the ANSI hooks (CreateMutexA, CreateMutexExA, OpenMutexA, lines 111–159, and IsSnippingMutexA) unless you've confirmed Snipping Tool calls them. The legacy Snipping Tool is a Unicode app, so these look like AI-generated padding. Are they intentional?
Remove the boilerplate at lines 28–39. Windhawk already includes windows.h and the Windhawk API and defines WH_MOD_ID, so the _WIN32_WINNT define, the __has_include(<windhawk_api.h>) guard and the WH_MOD_ID fallback (which is never used) can all go. The same applies to @compilerOptions -luser32: user32 is linked by default, and lm-regedit-multi-instance hooks FindWindowW without it. Wh_ModUninit only logs, so it can be removed as well.
Drop the "Snipping Tool" title match in IsSnippingWindow. Window titles are localized, so it only works on English systems, and the class-name check already covers every language.
README: the closing line refers to "my other mod Snipping tool escape quit", which isn't in the catalog. Link it once it's published, or remove the line for now.
Functionality notes

Non-critical observations and ideas about the feature behavior itself.

Concurrent instances share the legacy Snipping Tool's per-user settings, so whichever instance closes last decides the saved options. You might mention this in the README.
Code overview

For the maintainer: a map of the mod and what it touches outside its own process. Descriptive only — anything that needs a change is listed above. Line numbers refer to the mod source at commit c976375. This mod is new, so everything below is new.

Code regions

Line 1–11: metadata — targets snippingtool.exe (by file name), links -luser32, no settings.
Line 13–26: README — describes the mutex/window detection the mod defeats.
Line 28–39: preprocessor boilerplate — _WIN32_WINNT, <windows.h>, conditional windhawk_api.h include, WH_MOD_ID fallback.
Line 41–59: name-matching helpers — substring checks on mutex names (wide/ANSI) and on window class/title.
Line 61–109: wide mutex hooks — CreateMutexW/CreateMutexExW create a matching mutex unnamed instead of named; OpenMutexW fails with ERROR_FILE_NOT_FOUND for matching names.
Line 111–159: ANSI counterparts of the three mutex hooks.
Line 161–197: FindWindowW/FindWindowExW hooks — return NULL for any matching class or title, so existing instances aren't found.
Line 199–215: Wh_ModInit — installs the 8 hooks on the kernel32/user32 exports via raw Wh_SetFunctionHook.
Line 217–219: Wh_ModUninit — logs only.
Side effects of interest

None found — the mod only hooks kernel32/user32 functions in its host process. It doesn't touch files, the registry or the network, and doesn't reach into other processes. Its intended effect is that matching named mutexes are created unnamed, so the process stops coordinating with other instances through them.
Next steps:

/ai-review - after pushing fixes, to get a review of the updated code. You can repeat this as many times as you need, but each review is thorough and usually there's no need for more than 2-3 iterations.
/ready-for-reviewer - once you're satisfied with the state of the pull request, to hand it over to a human reviewer. If some findings above are left unaddressed, add a short note explaining why.
See the review process for details.

Important: Each reply that was generated by AI must be disclosed by including the following text in the reply: "Generated by AI. Model: (ai-model-name)".