Submission review
Note: This review was done by Claude. Due to the amount of submissions, doing a fully manual review for each pull request is no longer feasible. Thank you for understanding.

Remember: The AI reviewer can be wrong - it may misread code, flag correct code as broken, or suggest changes that make things worse. Treat its findings as suggestions to verify, not instructions to follow blindly. You're responsible for the code you submit, so if a finding doesn't hold up, say so instead of changing working code to satisfy it.

Please address the following issues. The items in the collapsed sections are optional, so it's your call whether to address them.

The new hotkey settings themselves are wired up correctly: every setting is read, and with the right API. But some long-standing problems in the code around them are what users hit every time they press the hotkey. Items 1, 2 and 4 below are exactly what the mod you forked from, Explorer Ctrl+N to New File, fixed in its v1.1 update (PR 4331). Porting those parts of its current code is probably the quickest way to fix them.

1. The new-folder work runs on the low-level keyboard hook thread, stalling keyboard input system-wide. HookThread (line 563) services the WH_KEYBOARD_LL hook and also runs PerformNewFolderAction itself (line 582). That function makes COM calls into every Explorer window and then sleeps for 150 ms (Sleep(150), line 509). Windows delivers each keystroke in the whole system to this thread and waits for it, so while the thread is busy, all keyboard input waits too. The keys that suffer are the ones the user types right after the hotkey, i.e. the new folder's name. If a wait exceeds LowLevelHooksTimeout, Windows 7 and later silently remove the hook, and the hotkey stops working until the mod is reloaded. Keep the hook thread doing nothing but the hook. Post the action to a second STA thread that runs its own message loop, and join it in Wh_ModUninit, as the upstream mod does: Worker_Init/Worker_Exit and WorkerThread.

2. The folder can be created in the wrong place. There are two separate causes:

GetTargetExplorerHWND (line 278) prefers the Explorer window under the mouse cursor to the foreground window. Say two Explorer windows sit side by side, and the user presses the hotkey in window A while the mouse rests over window B. The folder is created in B, even though the hook proc had already checked that A has focus. Pass the fg window from LowLevelKeybdProc along as the wParam of the posted WM_APP + 1 message, use that, and drop HitTestExplorerByCursor.
With tabs in Windows 11 Explorer, IWebBrowser2::get_HWND returns the same CabinetWClass frame for every tab. GetExplorerBrowserByHWND (line 287) therefore picks whichever tab comes first in IShellWindows, often a background tab. The folder is created in that tab's folder, and the rename is attempted in a view the user isn't looking at. Match the active tab instead, as upstream does in GetActiveShellTabHwnd and ResolveActiveShellView.
3. Shift as the only modifier breaks typing in Explorer. The new mod1 setting allows shift together with mod2: none. The hook swallows the key whenever an Explorer window has focus, including when the cursor is in the address bar, the search box or a rename box. So with Shift+A, typing a capital "A" anywhere in Explorer creates a folder instead, even while renaming the folder the mod just created. Remove shift from the mod1 options (Shift stays available as mod2), or reject a Shift-only combination in LoadSettings. Related: a combination like Ctrl+C, Ctrl+V or Ctrl+Z now replaces that command everywhere in Explorer, text boxes included. A one-line warning in the README or in the hotkey_char $description would help.

4. This should be a tool mod. The mod hooks no functions. All it does is install a system-wide WH_KEYBOARD_LL hook and drive Explorer through IShellWindows, and both work from any process. Running inside explorer.exe means a crash or stall in the mod takes the shell down with it. Also, with "Launch folder windows in a separate process" turned on, every explorer.exe instance installs its own system-wide keyboard hook. The upstream mod moved to @include windhawk.exe in v1.1 for these reasons. To convert, follow Mods as tools:

rename Wh_ModInit/Wh_ModSettingsChanged/Wh_ModUninit to WhTool_*;
paste the launcher boilerplate from that page verbatim;
drop the same-process checks (IsCurrentProcessWindow, and the fgPid == GetCurrentProcessId() test on line 619), because the Explorer windows will then belong to another process.
Optional improvements

Minor polish — none of this affects users, so it's your call.

LoadSettings (lines 188–203): Wh_GetStringSetting never returns NULL (it returns L"" when the value is missing), so the pX ? pX : L"..." and if (pX) checks never do anything. WindhawkUtils::StringSetting (add #include <windhawk_utils.h>) frees the string for you:
int mod1 = GetModifierVK(WindhawkUtils::StringSetting::make(L"mod1").get());
GetHotkeyVK (lines 154–171): the stored values for punctuation are words (comma, slash, …), so the switch on single punctuation characters can never be reached. Only a–z and 0–9 get there. Drop the switch; that also removes the need for towupper, which currently relies on a transitive <cwctype> include.
Settings label (line 106): in a YAML double-quoted string, \  is an escaped space, so the dropdown shows  (Backslash) without the backslash. Use '\ (Backslash)' (single quotes, no escapes) or "\\ (Backslash)".
MakeUniqueFolderName (line 392–393): formatting into a fixed wchar_t buf[256] truncates or fails on a long custom name, and then every attempt yields the same name. Build the string directly: base + L" (" + std::to_wstring(i) + L")".
Dead code (lines 432–434): folderPath in SelectAndRenameInWindow is computed and never used. Removing it also removes a wcscpy_s into a fixed-size buffer, which aborts the process if the path is too long.
Log prefixes: Wh_Log already tags every line with the mod, so the [CtrlQ] prefixes aren't needed. They're also misleading now that the hotkey is configurable.
README (line 18): "Formally" → "Formerly".
Functionality notes

Non-critical observations and ideas about the feature behavior itself.

Win and Alt modifiers: the hook swallows the key press, so Windows sees the modifier pressed and released with nothing in between. Releasing Win then opens the Start menu, and releasing Alt activates Explorer's menu/access-key mode. The usual fix is to send a tap of an unassigned key (0xE8, AutoHotkey's "menu mask key") before the modifier is released. See alt-drag and its ResendWinKeyReleaseMasked.
Auto-repeat and key-up leak through: only the first key press is swallowed (!g_nKeyDown, line 613). Auto-repeated presses while the combination is held, and the final key release, still reach Explorer. That's harmless for Ctrl+Q, but now that the key is configurable, holding a combination that means something in Explorer (Ctrl+N, Ctrl+W, Ctrl+D…) triggers that command too. Swallow the repeats and the matching key-up, as upstream does around line 1220.
Desktop support is ambiguous: this PR removes "including desktop" from the description, and the README (line 33) says the desktop isn't supported. Yet the code still handles it (lines 282–283, 324–342, 363–374, 483), and the hook still swallows the hotkey when the desktop has focus (line 618). It also works only some of the time, because the focused desktop window is often WorkerW rather than GetShellWindow(). Either remove the desktop code paths so the hotkey passes through on the desktop, or keep them and document desktop support.
Custom folder name isn't validated: the name is joined onto the path as-is. \ or / can put the folder somewhere else or make creation fail (..\x would create it in the parent folder). Reserved characters (:*?"<>|) make CreateDirectoryW fail with only a log line. Windows strips trailing dots and spaces, so the select/rename step can't find the folder afterwards. Sanitize the name in LoadSettings and fall back to "New folder" when it's invalid.
Sleep(150) is a timing guess: in a slow or network folder, the view may not list the new folder after 150 ms. SelectItem then fails silently and rename mode never starts. It doesn't crash either way, so the README's "prevents the crash" overstates what the sleep does. Retrying SelectItem for a bounded time on the worker thread is more reliable; upstream's StartRename uses this approach.
Key labels assume a US layout: VK_OEM_* codes depend on the keyboard layout. For example, VK_OEM_2 is / on a US keyboard but a different key on many others, so labels like "/ (Slash)" are only correct for US. multiply (VK_MULTIPLY) is the numpad * only. Worth a note in the setting's $description.
Code overview

For the maintainer: a map of the mod and what it touches outside its own process. Descriptive only — anything that needs a change is listed above. Line numbers refer to the mod source at commit 430b49a. 🟢 added / 🟡 updated / ⚪ unchanged, compared to the currently merged version.

Code regions

🟡 Line 1–11: metadata — renamed to "Explorer Ctrl + Key = New Folder", version 1.4.8.9, new @homepage; still @include explorer.exe.
🟡 Line 13–39: README — describes the configurable hotkey and folder name; says desktop is not supported.
🟢 Line 41–115: settings — mod1/mod2 modifier dropdowns, hotkey_char dropdown (A–Z, 0–9, punctuation), folderName string.
⚪ Line 118–134: includes and #pragma comment(lib) lines.
🟢 Line 136–225: settings state behind an SRW lock, string → virtual-key mapping (GetModifierVK, GetHotkeyVK), LoadSettings, and CheckModifiers (requires exactly the configured modifiers to be held).
⚪ Line 227–374: utilities — ComInit (per-call STA), URL → path conversion, picking the target window (Explorer window under the cursor → foreground window → desktop), IShellWindows lookup by HWND with a desktop FindWindowSW fallback, folder-path resolution, Desktop known-folder lookup.
🟡 Line 376–398: MakeUniqueFolderName — now uses the configured base name and appends  (N).
⚪ Line 400–467: CreateDirectoryW wrapper; finds the parent folder's PIDL and calls IShellView::SelectItem(SVSI_EDIT) to start the rename.
⚪ Line 469–512: PerformNewFolderAction — resolves the folder, creates the directory, sends SHChangeNotify(SHCNE_MKDIR), Sleep(150), then selects and renames.
⚪ Line 514–594: hook thread — created in KeybdHook_Init (above-normal priority), runs SetWindowsHookExW(WH_KEYBOARD_LL) plus a message loop that runs the action on WM_APP + 1 and quits on WM_APP; KeybdHook_Exit joins it.
🟡 Line 596–628: LowLevelKeybdProc — matches the configured key and modifiers when an Explorer window or the desktop of this process has focus, posts WM_APP + 1 and swallows the key press.
🟡 Line 630–644: Wh_ModInit (loads settings, starts the hook thread), Wh_ModUninit (joins it), Wh_ModSettingsChanged (reloads settings).
Side effects of interest

🟡 Line 376–405, 490–503: external file write — CreateDirectoryW creates a folder in the folder shown in the target Explorer window (or the Desktop) each time the hotkey is pressed; it persists (that's the feature). It is preceded by GetFileAttributesW/PathFileExistsW reads.
⚪ Line 287–346, 428–467: IPC — enumerates CLSID_ShellWindows and calls IWebBrowser2/IShellBrowser/IShellView on Explorer windows' threads (windows in another explorer.exe process are reached through out-of-process proxies), on each hotkey press.
⚪ Line 506: IPC — SHChangeNotify(SHCNE_MKDIR) notifies every shell change listener after the folder is created.
⚪ Line 563–594: other reach outside the process — installs a system-wide WH_KEYBOARD_LL hook (every keystroke in the session goes through this thread) from mod init until uninit.
🟡 Line 613–623: other reach outside the process — swallows the configured key press (returns 1) whenever an Explorer window or the desktop has focus.
Next steps:

/ai-review - after pushing fixes, to get a review of the updated code. You can repeat this as many times as you need, but each review is thorough and usually there's no need for more than 2-3 iterations.
/ready-for-reviewer - once you're satisfied with the state of the pull request, to hand it over to a human reviewer. If some findings above are left unaddressed, add a short note explaining why.
See the review process for details.

Important: Each reply that was generated by AI must be disclosed by including the following text in the reply: "Generated by AI. Model: (ai-model-name)".