Submission review
Note: This review was done by Claude. Due to the amount of submissions, doing a fully manual review for each pull request is no longer feasible. Thank you for understanding.

Remember: The AI reviewer can be wrong - it may misread code, flag correct code as broken, or suggest changes that make things worse. Treat its findings as suggestions to verify, not instructions to follow blindly. You're responsible for the code you submit, so if a finding doesn't hold up, say so instead of changing working code to satisfy it.

Please address the following issues. The items in the collapsed sections are optional, so it's your call whether to address them.

One item to address before this is ready. The mod is small and focused. It doesn't overlap any existing mod: the closest ones are lm-regedit-multi-instance and teams-multi-instance, and both target other apps.

Hooks may miss calls on the in-box WMP 12, and the README's "version agnostic" claim is untested

Lines 103–109 hook CreateMutexW and CreateFileW through the mod's own kernel32 import. On Windows 10/11 the real implementation of both functions lives in kernelbase.dll. Modules that link against API sets (api-ms-win-core-synch-*, api-ms-win-core-file-*) call kernelbase directly, and the in-box Windows 10/11 binaries usually do. Those calls can go around a hook placed at the kernel32 level. The .wmdb library files are most likely opened by wmp.dll, not by wmplayer.exe, so the Database Protection Sandbox could silently do nothing on stock WMP 12. Users would then get the "unsafe" multi-instance behavior while believing the library is protected. The only reported test is the Vista-era WMP 11 binaries, which import kernel32 directly, so a passing test there doesn't show that the current versions work, even though the README says they do.

Resolve both functions from kernelbase.dll. A hook there also catches every caller that goes through kernel32:

HMODULE kernelBase = GetModuleHandleW(L"kernelbase.dll");
auto pCreateMutexW = (decltype(&CreateMutexW))GetProcAddress(kernelBase, "CreateMutexW");
auto pCreateFileW = (decltype(&CreateFileW))GetProcAddress(kernelBase, "CreateFileW");
WindhawkUtils::SetFunctionHook(pCreateMutexW, CreateMutexW_Hook, &CreateMutexW_Original);
WindhawkUtils::SetFunctionHook(pCreateFileW, CreateFileW_Hook, &CreateFileW_Original);
after-effects-theme hooks kernelbase!CreateFileW the same way. Then please test with the in-box Windows Media Player on Windows 10 or 11 (called "Windows Media Player Legacy" on Windows 11). Turn on logging and confirm that both the mutex log line and the .wmdb log line appear in a second instance. Update the README to list only the versions you've actually tested. It should also say the mod targets the legacy wmplayer.exe only, not the new Windows 11 Media Player app.

Optional improvements

Minor polish — none of this affects users, so it's your call.

Simpler and sturdier mutex check (lines 54–74). OpenMutexW followed by CreateMutexW is a check-then-act sequence. It also asks for MUTEX_ALL_ACCESS, which fails with ERROR_ACCESS_DENIED when the first instance runs at a different integrity level (for example elevated). The second instance then isn't detected and the original single-instance behavior returns. Calling the original first and checking GetLastError() avoids both problems:
HANDLE h = CreateMutexW_Original(lpMutexAttributes, bInitialOwner, lpName);
if (h && GetLastError() == ERROR_ALREADY_EXISTS) {
    CloseHandle(h);
    g_isSecondaryInstance = true;
    std::wstring name = std::wstring(lpName) + L"_" + std::to_wstring(GetCurrentProcessId());
    h = CreateMutexW_Original(lpMutexAttributes, bInitialOwner, name.c_str());
}
return h;
If you keep OpenMutexW, SYNCHRONIZE access is enough to detect the mutex. Matching the full name (Microsoft_WMP_70_CheckForOtherInstanceMutex) instead of a substring is also more precise.
Unbounded wsprintfW into a 256-character buffer (lines 67–68). Mutex names can be up to MAX_PATH characters, and wsprintfW doesn't check the buffer size. With WMP's fixed name this can't actually overflow, but std::wstring (as above) or swprintf_s removes the question.
Use WindhawkUtils::SetFunctionHook (from <windhawk_utils.h>) instead of raw Wh_SetFunctionHook with void* casts. You get type checking and can drop the hand-written *_t typedefs.
Comments are misleading. Several of them read like AI filler and don't describe the code: "asynchronous stream routing", "Windhawk virtualization subsystem", "mapping matrix", "execution block", "Mutate the string pointer uniqueness dynamically". Plain comments, or none, would read better.
Wh_ModUninit only logs, so it can be removed.
settings.sandboxDatabase is written on the Windhawk engine thread and g_isSecondaryInstance is written on the WMP main thread, while both are read from whichever thread calls CreateFileW. std::atomic<bool> would make that well-defined. In practice the race is harmless.
Functionality notes

Non-critical observations and ideas about the feature behavior itself.

The database sandbox only partly protects the library. The hook clears GENERIC_WRITE and FILE_WRITE_DATA and nothing else:

It keeps FILE_APPEND_DATA, FILE_WRITE_ATTRIBUTES, DELETE, GENERIC_ALL and MAXIMUM_ALLOWED.
It doesn't touch dwCreationDisposition, and CREATE_ALWAYS can still truncate an existing file.
Writes made another way bypass it entirely: DeleteFileW, MoveFileExW/ReplaceFileW (a write-to-temp-then-rename save), CreateFile2, NtCreateFile.
The README's "preventing … library data file corruption" promises more than the code delivers. Either tone the claim down or strip a broader set of write rights (and map write dispositions to OPEN_EXISTING).

How WMP reacts to the read-only database is untested. Once its write calls start failing, the second instance might show errors, or might decide the library is corrupt and rebuild it. The primary instance probably also holds the .wmdb open with restrictive sharing, so the second instance's read-only open could fail with a sharing violation instead of succeeding. Run a quick test with two instances, each making some library changes, and describe the outcome in the README.

wcsstr(lpFileName, L".wmdb") is case-sensitive. WMP's own file names are lowercase, so this is fine in practice, but .WMDB wouldn't match.

Code overview

For the maintainer: a map of the mod and what it touches outside its own process. Descriptive only — anything that needs a change is listed above. Line numbers refer to the mod source at commit c02be16. This mod is new, so everything below is new.

Code regions

Line 1–9: Metadata. @include wmplayer.exe, no @architecture (so both 32-bit and 64-bit).
Line 11–27: README.
Line 29–35: Settings block with one boolean, sandboxDatabase (default true).
Line 37–51: <windows.h> include, settings struct, g_isSecondaryInstance flag, typedefs and original-function pointers for the two hooks.
Line 53–74: CreateMutexW hook. If a mutex whose name contains CheckForOtherInstanceMutex already exists (checked with OpenMutexW), it marks the process as secondary and creates a <name>_<pid> mutex instead, which defeats WMP's single-instance check.
Line 76–89: CreateFileW hook. In secondary instances with the sandbox setting on, it clears GENERIC_WRITE/FILE_WRITE_DATA on opens of any path containing .wmdb.
Line 91–94: LoadSettings. Reads sandboxDatabase.
Line 96–112: Wh_ModInit. Loads settings and hooks CreateMutexW and CreateFileW through the kernel32 import.
Line 114–117: Wh_ModUninit. Logs only.
Line 119–123: Wh_ModSettingsChanged. Reloads settings.
Side effects of interest

Line 59: IPC: OpenMutexW(MUTEX_ALL_ACCESS) on the WMP single-instance mutex (…CheckForOtherInstanceMutex, session namespace) to detect another running WMP. Runs once at WMP startup, inside the CreateMutexW hook. The handle is closed immediately.
Line 67–69: IPC: in a secondary instance, creates a session-wide named mutex <original name>_<pid> in place of the shared one. It lives for the life of the process.
Line 78–88: external file read/write: the mod never touches files itself. It changes the access mask of WMP's own CreateFileW opens of *.wmdb (the library database under %LOCALAPPDATA%\Microsoft\Media Player), removing write access in secondary instances. Nothing persists after the mod is disabled.
Next steps:

/ai-review - after pushing fixes, to get a review of the updated code. You can repeat this as many times as you need, but each review is thorough and usually there's no need for more than 2-3 iterations.
/ready-for-reviewer - once you're satisfied with the state of the pull request, to hand it over to a human reviewer. If some findings above are left unaddressed, add a short note explaining why.
See the review process for details.

Important: Each reply that was generated by AI must be disclosed by including the following text in the reply: "Generated by AI. Model: (ai-model-name)".