Submission review
Note: This review was done by Claude. Due to the amount of submissions, doing a fully manual review for each pull request is no longer feasible. Thank you for understanding.

Remember: The AI reviewer can be wrong - it may misread code, flag correct code as broken, or suggest changes that make things worse. Treat its findings as suggestions to verify, not instructions to follow blindly. You're responsible for the code you submit, so if a finding doesn't hold up, say so instead of changing working code to satisfy it.

Please address the following issues. The items in the collapsed sections are optional, so it's your call whether to address them.

Thanks for crediting both source mods. The main concern is overlap: everything this mod does already exists in two mods in the catalog.

1. Duplicates existing mods. Every functional line comes from an existing mod, and the mod adds no new logic:

Section 1 (ExplorerFrame_CoCreateInstanceHook plus its Wh_ModInit block, lines 49–50, 72, 83–93, 208–217) is a verbatim copy of Windows 7 Command Bar.
Sections 2–3 (lines 100–163, and the shell32DllHooks entries) are a verbatim copy of Aerexplorer's "Views dropdown on left" and "Command bar icons" code. Aerexplorer already ships these as its leftviews / cmdbaricons options, next to its own noribbon option.
The only real difference is that Aerexplorer refuses to load on a Windows 11 ExplorerFrame.dll. So on Windows 11, its two command-bar options aren't available on top of Windows 7 Command Bar. That gap is real, but it's two small options. The catalog generally prefers extending an existing mod over adding a third, near-identical one. Users would otherwise have to choose between overlapping mods, and enabling this one alongside either source mod hooks the same functions twice.

Suggested path: open an issue or PR on Windows 7 Command Bar (ItsProfessional) to add leftviews / cmdbaricons there. That mod is what Windows 11 users already use to get this command bar, and these options are a natural addition to it. If you and the maintainer still prefer a separate mod, the README should explain who it's for and how it relates to the other two: e.g., "Windows 11 users who want Vista-style command bar icons/layout without Aerexplorer; replaces Windows 7 Command Bar, don't enable both."

2. README: add a screenshot and list the Windows versions you tested. This is a purely visual mod, so a screenshot or before/after image would help users a lot. Allowed hosts are i.imgur.com and raw.githubusercontent.com.

Please also state which Windows builds you tested on. The icon code reads the icon index from a hard-coded offset inside shell32's internal ExplorerCommandItem struct (*((DWORD *)pItem + 10), line 129). Aerexplorer only validated that offset on Windows 10, since it doesn't run on Windows 11. This mod has no version check and is clearly aimed at Windows 11 too, because it blocks the Windows 11 command bar CLSID. Please confirm the icons are correct on the Windows 11 builds you support. If the layout differs there, the mod would show wrong icons.

Optional improvements

Minor polish — none of this affects users, so it's your call.

Unused dependencies. #include <commctrl.h> (line 43) and @compilerOptions -lcomctl32 -luser32 -lole32 (line 11) aren't used. No comctl32 or ole32 functions are called, and IsEqualCLSID is an inline from guiddef.h. The STDCALL macro (lines 56/61) is also unused. You can drop all of them, along with the @compilerOptions line.

Dead 32-bit branches with latent calling-convention bugs. The mod is @architecture x86-64, so the #else (32-bit) halves of the macros at lines 53–63 and 128–132 never compile. They would also be wrong if they did:

IsRightSideCommand_orig/_hook are declared __fastcall while the symbol string says __stdcall.
ExplorerFrame_CoCreateInstanceHook lacks WINAPI.
Either drop the 32-bit branches or fix those signatures.

Hooking CoCreateInstance (lines 209–217):

Use the type-safe WindhawkUtils::SetFunctionHook instead of raw Wh_SetFunctionHook with void* casts, and check that GetProcAddress succeeded.
The variable named hExplorerFrame actually holds the combase/API-set module, so rename it (e.g. hCombase).
The two raw INT64 compares at line 85 would read better as a named DEFINE_GUID for {6480100B-5A83-4D1E-9F69-8AE5A88E9A33} plus IsEqualCLSID. Example:
HMODULE hCombase = GetModuleHandleW(L"combase.dll");
auto pCoCreateInstance = (decltype(&CoCreateInstance))GetProcAddress(hCombase, "CoCreateInstance");
if (pCoCreateInstance) {
    WindhawkUtils::SetFunctionHook(pCoCreateInstance, CoCreateInstance_Hook, &CoCreateInstance_Original);
}
Getting the shell32.dll handle (line 220). GetModuleHandleW(L"shell32.dll") only works if shell32 is already loaded when Wh_ModInit runs. Most Explorer mods use LoadLibraryExW(L"shell32.dll", nullptr, LOAD_LIBRARY_SEARCH_SYSTEM32) so they don't depend on load order. Examples: Aerexplorer and Classic Explorer Menu Bar.

Functionality notes

Non-critical observations and ideas about the feature behavior itself.

All-or-nothing init. All five shell32 symbol hooks are required. On a build where any of them fails to resolve, Wh_ModInit returns FALSE, and that also drops the CoCreateInstance block. The ribbon/command-bar restoration doesn't depend on those symbols, so decide whether it should still apply in that case.
When setting changes apply. Wh_ModSettingsChanged only updates the flags. The hooks run when a command bar is (re)built, so a change shows up only after navigating or opening a new window. The comment "Refresh active windows naturally" (line 241) suggests otherwise. A short note in the README (or the setting descriptions) would avoid confusion.
Code overview

For the maintainer: a map of the mod and what it touches outside its own process. Descriptive only — anything that needs a change is listed above. Line numbers refer to the mod source at commit 8b29956. This mod is new, so everything below is new.

Code regions

Line 1–13: metadata. Targets explorer.exe, x86-64, MIT; links comctl32/user32/ole32.
Line 15–29: README with credits to Aerexplorer and Windows 7 Command Bar, plus a feature list. No screenshot.
Line 31–40: settings: cmdbaricons and leftviews, both booleans defaulting to true.
Line 42–63: includes, the CLSID_UIRibbonFramework / IID_UIRibbonFramework GUIDs, and calling-convention macros (THISCALL/STHISCALL, with 32-bit branches).
Line 65–78: global settings struct and LoadModSettings (two Wh_GetIntSetting reads).
Line 83–93: CoCreateInstance hook. Returns REGDB_E_CLASSNOTREG for the Windows 11 command bar CLSID {6480100B-5A83-4D1E-9F69-8AE5A88E9A33} and for UIRibbonFramework, so Explorer falls back to the legacy Vista/7 command bar. Copied from win7-command-bar.
Line 100–120: shell32 layout hooks: IsRightSideCommand, CCommandFolder::_AppendRightSideCommands, and CCommandFolder::_AppendOrganizeCommand. With leftviews, the right-side commands (Views etc.) are appended right after Organize instead of on the right. Copied from Aerexplorer.
Line 127–163: shell32 icon hooks. CSplitButton::UpdateIcon is suppressed when cmdbaricons is on. CSplitButton::_UpdateDisplay forces the icon using an index read at a hard-coded offset in ExplorerCommandItem, falling back to the blank-document icon via Shell_GetCachedImageIndexW (resolved with GetProcAddress). Copied from Aerexplorer.
Line 171–202: shell32DllHooks: 5 required SYMBOL_HOOKs targeting shell32.dll.
Line 204–232: Wh_ModInit. Loads settings, hooks CoCreateInstance in the api-ms-win-core-com-l1-1-0 / combase.dll module, then calls HookSymbols on the already-loaded shell32.dll. Returns FALSE if shell32 isn't loaded or any symbol is missing.
Line 234–242: Wh_ModUninit (log only) and Wh_ModSettingsChanged (reloads the two flags).
Side effects of interest

None found. The mod only hooks functions inside explorer.exe (COM activation and shell32 internals). It does no file, registry, network or IPC access and changes no system settings.

Next steps:

/ai-review - after pushing fixes, to get a review of the updated code. You can repeat this as many times as you need, but each review is thorough and usually there's no need for more than 2-3 iterations.
/ready-for-reviewer - once you're satisfied with the state of the pull request, to hand it over to a human reviewer. If some findings above are left unaddressed, add a short note explaining why.
See the review process for details.

Important: Each reply that was generated by AI must be disclosed by including the following text in the reply: "Generated by AI. Model: (ai-model-name)".